Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions and Organizations WEB.ARC.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Coalition of Graduate Employee Unions Archived Website, Jul 9, 2011 - Jul 8, 2013; Coalition of Graduate Employee Unions
  The Coalition of Graduate Employee Unions was formed in 1992 to support the organization of new graduate employee unions; to strengthen established unions; and to provide a forum for graduate employee unionists to meet, share information and work together toward common goals. The coalition holds an annual conference featuring workshops on organizing, leadership development, negotiation strategies, and member mobilization. Each year, the conference is hosted by a different union; here are the locations and hosting unions (and international union affiliations) of the past ten conferences. This website is set up in a “wiki” format.
  Graduate teaching assistants |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Coalition of Labor Union Women Archived Website, Sep 25, 2007 - ongoing; Coalition of Labor Union Women (U.S.).
  Formed in 1974, Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) is a nonpartisan organization whose primary mission is to unify all union women in a viable organization to determine our common problems and concerns and to develop action programs within the framework of our unions to deal effectively with our objectives. With members from 54 international and national unions across the U.S. and Canada, CLUW has a network of more than 40 chapters. CLUW is endorsed by the AFL-CIO and its international and national unions.
  Employee rights |z United States.; Women labor union leaders |z United States.; Women labor union members |z United States.
- Council of School Supervisors and Administrators Archived Website, Apr 14, 2014-ongoing; American Federation of School Administrators. Local 1, Council of Supervisors and Administrators (New York, N.Y.).
  The Council of School Supervisors and Administrators is the collective bargaining unit for 6,100 Principals, Assistant Principals, Supervisors and Education Administrators who work in the NYC public schools and 200 Directors and Assistant Directors who work in city- subsidized Centers for Early Childhood Education. CSA was formed from many professional organizations that represented supervisors and administrators as the Council of Supervisory Associations in 1962 to fight for collective bargaining rights with the then NYC Board of Education. In 1968, CSA became a labor union and changed its name to the Council of Supervisors and Administrators. CSA is Local 1 of the American Federation of School Administrators, AFL-CIO, located in Washington, DC. CSA is also affiliated with the NYS Federation of School Administrators, which is, in turn, a member of the NYS School Administrators Consortium. The website contains its newsletter, CSA News, information on workshops and training, political action campaigns, agreements and contracts, and additional photographs and videos.
- Committee for Free Trade Unionism Archived Website, Sep 18, 2009 - ongoing; Committee for Free Trade Unionism.
  The Committee for Free Trade Unionism (CFTU), was founded in ca. 2008 by Thomas R. Donahue, President Emeritus of the AFL-CIO, and appears to be largely composed of individuals involved with the group Social Democrats USA. CFTU aims to promote trade union freedom by working with a worldwide network of trade union experts and other groups committed to the advancement of free trade unionism, galvanize the efforts of international labor, and providing defenses against trade union persecution and oppression anywhere in the world.
  Employee rights.; Human rights.; Labor unions.
- Communications Workers of America Archived Website, May 24, 2008 - ongoing; Communications Workers of America.
  Communications Workers of America (CWA), founded in 1947, is America's largest communications and media union, represents over 700,000 men and women in both private and public sectors, including over half a million workers who are employed in telecommunications, broadcasting, cable TV, journalism, publishing, electronics and general manufacturing, as well as airline customer service, government service, health care, education and other fields. The union includes some 1,200 chartered local unions across the United States, Canada and Puerto Rico. Members live in approximately 10,000 communities, making CWA one of the most geographically diverse unions. CWA is headquartered in Washington, DC, and affiliated with the AFL-CIO, the Canadian Labour Congress, and Union Network International
  Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Communications Workers of America Local 1060 Archived Website, Nov 27, 2012 - ongoing; Communications Workers of America. Local 1060 (North Plainfield, N.J.).
  CWA Local 1060 represents workers at Lucent (formerly Bell Labs, in Murray Hill, NJ). The website contains information on benefits, minutes, financials, and news.
- Communications Workers of America Local 1109 Archived Website, Nov 26, 2012 - ongoing; Communications Workers of America. Local 1109.
  The Communications Workers of America Local 1109 represents over 2,000 telecommunications technicians and customer service representatives in Brooklyn, New York. The website contains information on benefits, political action campaigns, their publication, the Wire, and news.
- Communications Workers of America, District 1 Archived Website, Mar 7, 2012 - ongoing; Communications Workers of America. District 1.
  District 1 of the Communications Workers of America (CWA) includes 327 CWA local unions in New York, New Jersey, New England, and eastern Canada. Members are employed in many different sectors of the economy including, telecommunications; health care; higher education; manufacturing; broadcast and cable television; commercial printing and newspapers; state, local, and country government.
  Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z Canada.; Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z Middle Atlantic States.; Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New England.
- Communications Workers of America, District 2-13 Archived Website, Mar 2, 2009 - ongoing; Communications Workers of America. District 2.
  District 2-13 is responsible for servicing all CWA locals in Pennsylvania, Maryland, Delaware, Virginia, West Virginia, and the District of Columbia. Members are employed in many different sectors of the economy including, telecommunications; health care; higher education; manufacturing; broadcast and cable television; commercial printing and newspapers; state, local, and country government.
  Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z District of Columbia.; Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z Maryland.; Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z Virginia.; Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z West Virginia.
- Communications Workers of America, District 4 Archived Website, Apr 19, 2014-ongoing; Communications Workers of America. District 4.
  Communications Workers of America District 4, representing a variety of workers in the states of Illinois, Indiana, Ohio, Michigan and Wisconsin. CWA District 4 includes over 200 local unions that represent workers in telecommunications, informational technology, publishing, print and electronic media, manufacturing, higher education, local government and health care. The website contains news listings, bargaining agreements, their political action committee, and event listings.
- Communications Workers of America, Local 1032 Archived Website, Feb 26, 2009 - ongoing; Communications Workers of America. Local 1032 (Ewing, N.J.).
  Communications Workers of America Local 1032 represents about 6,000 workers in a variety of professions and fields in several New Jersey State Departments, the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey, several New Jersey towns and counties as well as several private sector work sites.
  Telecommunication |x Labor unions |z New Jersey.; Telecommunication |x Labor unions |z New York.
- Communications Workers of America, Local 1101 Archived Website, Feb 27, 2009 - ongoing; Communications Workers of America. Local 1101 (New York, N.Y.).
  Communication Workers of America, Local 1101 is based in New York, New York.
  Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Communications Workers of America, Local 1103 Archived Website, Mar 5, 2009 - ongoing; Communications Workers of America. Local 1103.
  Communication Workers of America, Local 1103 is based in Port Chester, New York.
- Communications Workers of America, Local 1150 Archived Website, Mar 9, 2010 - ongoing; Communications Workers of America. Local 1150 (New York, N.Y.).
  Communication Workers of America, Local 1150 is based in New York, NY, and represents landline technicians in the New York and New Jersey metropolitan area. The website contains union news.
  Trade-unions--Telephone company employees--New York (N.Y.)
- Communications Workers of America, Local 1153 Archived Website, Feb 26, 2009 - ongoing; Communications Workers of America. Local 1153 (Valhalla, N.Y.).
  Communications Workers of America, Local 1153 was chartered in 1975, after more than 500 members of the Manhattan-based Local 1150 petitioned for a new local to represent American Telephone & Telegraph's Long Lines (long distance) employees working in the White Plains and Mount Kisco area. 1153 consists of three sections: Plant (construction and maintenance), Traffic (operators) and Administrative (clerical). Local 1153 advocates for many issues, including job losses, job pressures, seniority rights, the creation of new job titles, health and safety, and discrimination based on sex and race. The website contains by-laws, bargaining reports, other reports, event listings, and contracts.
  American Telephone and Telegraph Company |x Employees; Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Communications Workers of America, Local 1180 Archived Website, Sep 24, 2007 - ongoing; Communications Workers of America. Local 1180 (New York, N.Y.).
  Local 1180 is an affiliate of the Communications Workers of America (CWA), representing over 8,000 workers in the New York City area. Members work in the public sector, but the union also represents workers at the Board of Education, the Housing Authority, the Transit Authority, the School Construction Authority, the state's Unified Court System; at private companies such as the Jacob Javits Convention Center; and at not-for-profit organizations including Planned Parenthood of New York City, the ASPCA, Human Rights First, and Human Rights Watch. The website includes information on health and retiree benefits, training programs, news, negotiations, their newsletter Communique, and other multimedia.
- Cyberunions Archived Website, Nov 10, 2011 - ongoing; Cyberunions
  Cyberunions, created by Walter Pantland, works to get trade unions to use technology to organize and building an open source labor movement. The site contains both theoretical pieces on and more practical resources for activists. The website also produces a podcast on trade unions, technology, and economics.
  Cyberspace |x Political aspects.; Labor unions |x Organizing.
- Domestic Workers United Archived Website, May 4, 2011 - ongoing; Domestic Workers United
  Initially founded in 2000 by the Women Workers Project of Committee of Against Anti-Asian Violence, the Domestic Workers United (DWU) is an organization of Caribbean, Latina and African nannies, housekeepers, and caregivers for the elderly in New York, organizing for fair labor standards and to help build a movement to end exploitation and oppression. DWU organizes workers from the Caribbean, Africa and Latin America, and coordinates with the other domestic workers organizations through the NY Domestic Workers Justice Coalition to build the power of the entire workforce.
  Foreign Workers |z United States; Household employees |z United States.
- Embedded With Organized Labor Archived Website, Dec 2, 2011 - Dec 2, 2012; Early, Steve
  Embedded With Organized Labor is the labor blog by Steve Early. Steve Early is a labor journalist and lawyer who has written for numerous publications. He is the author of Embedded With Organized Labor: Journalistic Reflections on the Class War at Home and The Civil Wars in U.S. Labor. Early was a Boston-based international representative or organizer for the Communications Workers of America for 27 years, and is a member of the editorial advisory committees of three independent labor publications: Labor Notes, New Labor Forum and Working USA.
  Blogs.; Labor movement |z United States.
- Employee Free Choice Act Now! Archived Website, Dec 23, 2008 - Dec 24, 2010
  The Employee Free Choice Act was a legislative bill that was introduced into both chambers of the U.S. Congress on March 10, 2009. The bill's purpose was to, “amend the National Labor Relations Act to establish an efficient system to enable employees to form, join, or assist labor organizations [unions], to provide for mandatory injunctions for unfair labor practices during organizing efforts, and for other purposes." This website was a petition website in support of the act. The central part of the legislation would have provided for automatic certification of unions if a majority of potential members had signed unionization cards.
  Labor laws and legislation |z United States.
- Excluded Workers Congress Archived Website, Oct 19, 2011 - Jan 17, 2014; The Inter-Alliance Dialogue
  The Excluded Worker Congress consists of networks of organizations that represent a base of workers that are either by law or by practice excluded from the right to organize. The nine sectors of the Excluded Workers Congress include domestic workers, farm workers, taxi drivers, restaurant workers, day laborers, guest workers, workers from Southern right- to-work states, workfare workers and formerly incarcerated workers. They are a project of the Inter-Alliance Dialogue, an alliance of Grassroots Global Justice Alliance, Jobs with Justice, National Day Labor Organizing Network, National Domestic Worker Alliance, Pushback Network, and Right to the City Alliance and affiliated with the AFL-CIO and other unions.
  Employee rights.; Syndicalism.
- Farm Labor Organizing Committee (FLOC) Archived Website, Dec 4, 2009 - ongoing; Farm Labor Organizing Committee
  The Farm Labor Organizing Committee, AFL-CIO, (FLOC), founded in 1967, is a labor union representing migrant farm workers in the Midwestern United States and North Carolina.
  Agricultural laborers |x Labor unions |z United States.; Hispanic American agricultural laborers.
- Fast Food Forward Archived Website, Mar 1, 2013 - Sep 4, 2014; Fast Food Forward
  Fast Food Forward is a movement of New York City fast food workers to raise wages and gain rights at work. The website contains a petition.
  Restaurants |x Employees |x Labor unions.
- Fruit of Labor Singing Ensemble Archived Website, Jul 2, 2012 - ongoing; Fruit of Labor Singing Ensemble
  The Fruit of Labor Singing Ensemble is a labor affiliated singing group that grew out of the struggle of organizing African American workers in the “Black Belt" region of North Carolina and the South. Their music captures the working class’ history of community and workplace struggles. The website features their music and event listings.
- Glass, Molders, Pottery, Plastics and Allied Workers International Union (GMP) Archived Website, Dec 4, 2009 - ongoing; Glass, Molders, Pottery, Plastics and Allied Workers International Union
  The Glass, Molders, Pottery, Plastics & Allied Workers (GMP) International Union, with its origins dating back to 1842 represents thousands of workers in the glass, molders, plastics, pottery, cast metals, fiberglass, defense, fine china, glass and plastic containers, insulation and sanitary-ware industries as well as workers in government, healthcare and a variety of other industries. The GMP International Union currently belongs to the AFL-CIO, CLC and is active in the Union Label and Service Trades Department as well as the Maritime Trades Department.
  Ceramic industries |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Graduate Student Organizing Committee (GSOC), UAW Local 2110 Archived Website, Jul 6, 2011 - Jan 6, 2014; International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America. Local 2110. (New York, N.Y.)
  GSOC/UAW Local 2110 is the union of teaching, research and graduate assistants at New York University. As the chosen representative of the majority of NYU graduate employees, the Graduate Student Organizing Committee (GSOC) is committed to restoring collective bargaining rights for our membership and forcing NYU to once again recognize our union, as it did when GSOC and NYU signed a contract governing graduate employment in 2002. Collective bargaining gives employees a say in their working conditions by empowering chosen representatives of those workers to negotiate with employers over issues like pay, workload protections, workplace safety and benefits.
  Graduate teaching assistants |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; New York University |x Faculty.
- Graduate Student Organizing Committee (GSOC-UAW) Local 2110 Archived Website, Oct 13, 2013-ongoing; International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America. Local 2110. (New York, N.Y.)
  The Graduate Student Organizing Committee (GSOC-UAW Local 2110) is the union for graduate employees at New York University (NYU) and the Polytechnic Institute of New York University. This includes teaching assistants, research assistants, and graduate assistants. The Polytechnic Institute organizes science and engineering graduate students. The union was established in 1998 and negotiated their first contract with NYU in 2002. In 2004, the National Labor Relations Board reversed the Brown University decision, declaring private universities are not required to bargain with graduate employees and leading to NYU not negotiating a new contract. Over the next years, GSOC continued the fight for recognition at NYU, and currently gathering signatures to get NYU to negotiate a contract restoring healthcare benefits. The website contains information about the union and its Polytechnic Institute affiliate (SET-UAW), campaigns, news, and event listings.
  Graduate teaching assistants |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Independent Association of Publishers' Employees CWA Local 1096 Archived Website, Mar 1, 2013 - ongoing; Independent Association of Publishers' Employees CWA Local 1096
  The Independent Association of Publishers' Employees Inc. (IAPE) was founded 1937 by a group of Dow Jones & Company employees in Manhattan, NY. It has grown to represent employees at various parts of Dow Jones & Company in many locations across the North American continent. In 1997, by vote of the membership, IAPE became Local 1096 of the Communications Workers of America (CWA). Subsequently, IAPE joined The Newspaper Guild sector of the CWA by action of the Board of Directors. The website contains bylaws, grievances, benefits, budgets, their contract, meeting minutes, and news.
  Newspaper employees |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Industrial Workers of the World Archived Website, Jul 28, 2009 - ongoing; Industrial Workers of the World.
  The Industrial Workers of the World, founded in 1905, is a member-run union for all workers, dedicated to organizing on the job, in industries and communities. IWW members are organizing to win better conditions and build a world with economic democracy. IWW works to change the atmosphere in workplaces run for the benefit of workers and communities. The IWW contends that all workers should be united as a class and that the wage system should be abolished. They may be best known for the Wobbly Shop model of workplace democracy, in which workers elect recallable delegates, and other norms of grassroots democracy (self-management) are implemented.
  Labor movement |x Political activity |z United States.; Syndicalism |z United States.
- International Alliance of Theatrical and Stage Employees, Local 52 Archived Website, Feb 8, 2009 - ongoing; International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees and Moving Picture Machine Operators of the United States and Canada. Local 52
  International Alliance of Theatrical and Stage Employees, Local 52 was founded in the early 1920s, and was officially chartered by the International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees (IATSE) in 1924. The local’s jurisdiction includes, New York, New Jersey, Delaware, Pennsylvania (with the exception of Pittsburgh), and Connecticut. The labor union represents technicians, artisans and craftspeople in the entertainment industry, including live theatre, motion picture and television production, and trade shows. The website includes information on films and television series currently being filmed in the local's jurisdiction, membership applications, links and other resources.
  Theaters |x Employees |X Labor unions |z United States.
- International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees, Moving Picture Technicians, Artists and Allied Crafts of the United States, Its Territories and Canada (IATSE) Archived Website, Dec 4, 2009 - ongoing; International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employes, Moving Picture Technicians, Artists and Allied Crafts of the United States and Canada.
  The International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees, Moving Picture Technicians, Artists and Allied Crafts of the United States, Its Territories and Canada was originally chartered by the American Federation of Labor as the National Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees in 1893. With 110,000 members, the labor union represents technicians, artisans and craftspeople in the entertainment industry, including live theatre, motion picture and television production, and trade shows.
  Motion picture industry |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.; Theaters |x Employees |X Labor unions |z United States.
- International Association of Bridge, Structural, Ornamental and Reinforcing Iron Workers (Ironworkers) Archived Website, Dec 7, 2009 - ongoing; International Association of Bridge, Structural, Ornamental and Reinforcing Iron Workers (Ironworkers)
  The International Association of Bridge, Structural, Ornamental and Reinforcing Iron Workers Union, AFL-CIO, founded in 1896, represents primarily construction workers, as well as shipbuilding and metal fabrication employees. The current membership stands at approximately 140,000, with 15,000 apprentices.
  Iron and steel workers |x Labor unions |z United States.
- International Association of Fire Fighters (IAFF) Archived Website, Dec 12, 2009 - ongoing; International Association of Fire Fighters
  The International Association of Fire Fighters (IAFF), found in 1918 and headquartered in Washington, DC, represents more than 295,000 full-time professional fire fighters and paramedics who protect 85 percent of the nation’s population. More than 3,100 affiliates and their members protect communities in every state in the United States and in Canada. The IAFF is one of the most active lobbying organizations in Washington; its Political Action Committee, FIREPAC, is among the top 25 federal PACs among the more than 4,000 in the country.
  Fire fighters |x Labor unions |z United States.
- International Association of Heat and Frost Insulators and Allied Workers Archived Website, Dec 4, 2009 - ongoing; International Association of Heat and Frost Insulators and Allied Workers